Davis, Jackson; Papers apap141
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Subject Files, 1956-1997; Undated; 8; 3.17 cubic ft.
  - Ebenezer Howard Project, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 68)
  - Ecologic, Correspondence, 1995 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 69)
  - Ecology, Plant and Animal, News Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 70)
  - Economics, News Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 71)
  - Economics, Social Value Accounting, News Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 72)
  - "Endangered Pine Bush Lepidoptera," Robert Divig and John Cryan, 1974 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 73)
  - "Energy Goals and the Environment" Conference, Conference Materials, 1971 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 74)
  - Environment, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 75)
  - Environmental Clearinghouse of Schenectady, 1971-1972 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 76)
  - Environmental Consulting for the Home, Leaflet, Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 77)
  - Environmental Decisions Commission, Minutes, 1971 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 78)
  - "Environmental Design: A Citizen's Primer," Department of Floriculture, Cornell University, Undated (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 79)
  - Environmental Education, 1970-1972 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 80)
  - Environmental Legislation Study Group, Notes, 1971 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 81)
  - Environmental Management, EPA Reports, 1972 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 82)
  - "Environmental Plan for New York State, Preliminary Edition," Department of Environmental Conservation, 1973 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 83)
  - Environmental Quality Bond Act, Draft Regulations, 1972 (Box 1 (8-Subject Files), Folder 84)
  - Environment Reporter, 1971; 1974-1975 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Environmental Teach-In, 1970 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Farm Management, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - "A feasibility Study for Development of Land Along the Hudson, Prepared for RPI", 1967 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - First Unitarian Society, Presentation Notes, 1972 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Five Rivers Environmental Education Center, 1968; 1971-1972 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Five Rivers Environmental Education Center, Grant Proposal, 1971 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Five Rivers Environmental Education Center, Pamphlets, 1969; 1972 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Five Rivers Environmental Education Center, The Tributary, Newsletter, 1972 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Fliers and Handbills, 1991; 1995; 1997; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Food and Agriculture, 1974-1975 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Food and Food Additives, News Clippings, 1969 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Fund Raising, News Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Future, News Clippings, 1969 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Friends of Grafton Lake State Park, Leaflet, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Gardening, 1973; 1988 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Gas Guzzlers Campaign, Handbill, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - George Landis Arboretum, Handbill, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Global Re-Leaf, Leaflets, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Great Lakes Water Quality Guidance, Leaflet, 1983 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Greenpeace, 1989; 1993; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - "Greenways in the Hudson River Valley, 1988 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - "Groundwater Supply Source Protection", Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Handwritten Notes, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Hawaii, News Clippings, 1969 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Health, News Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Health Research, Inc., Conference Notes, 1993 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Help Your Environment Project, News Clippings, 1970 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - High Schools, 1972; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Honest Weight Food Co-op Coop Scoop, Newsletter, 1994-1995 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Housing, 1969-1971 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Hudson River Valley Greenway, Publications, 1991; 1994; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Hudson Valley Grass Roots Energy and Environmental Network The Hudson Valley Green Times, Newsletter, 1991; 1994 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Human Behavior, News Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Hunger Action Network of New York State, 1994; Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - "The Impact of Economic Development and Land Utilization Policies on the Quality of the Environment," Center for the Environment and Man, 1974 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Indoor Air Pollution, Articles, 1973; 1984-1985 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Indoor Air Pollution, Wood Burning, Pamphlets, 1983 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Industrial Research, Articles, 1969-1970 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Information Retrieval, Science and Technology, 1975 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Institute for Science and Interdisciplinary Studies, 1996 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - "Introduction to a Theory of Estimation", Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Job Applications, 1968; 1970 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Johnny Horizon Campaign, 1971-1972 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Johnny Horizon Campaign, Pamphlets, 1971-1972; 1976 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Johnny Horizon Campaign, Posters, 1971-1972 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Keep New York State Clean Program, 1973-1974 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Kids Against Pollution KAP News, Newsletter, 1994 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Knolls Action Project, 1994 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Land Use, News Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Land Use and the Environment, 1956; 1967 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Land Use Legislation, 1973; 1975 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Land Use, Pamphlets, 1971 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Land Use, Publications, 1973-1976 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Learning Alliance, Program Listings, 1994-1995 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Legal Action, News Clippings, 1969 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Legislation, Federal, News Clippings, 1969 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Legislation, New York State, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Letters to the Editor and Editorials, 1969-1971 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - "Library Service to a Starving Population," Jackson Davis, 1970 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - Litter Control Law, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 61)
  - Local Environmental Councils, 1970-1973 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 62)
  - Local Environmental Groups, Contact Lists, 1970-1973 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 63)
  - "Man and His Environment," Part 2, Edward Renshaw, 1970 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 64)
  - Nassau, Town of, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 65)
  - March 19th Coalition, Fliers, 1997 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 66)
  - National and State Parks, News Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 67)
  - National Catastrophe, News Clippings, 1969 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 68)
  - National Land Use Policy, 1974-1975 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 69)
  - National Science Foundation Research Applied to National Needs, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 70)
  - Natural Brands / Environmentally Yours, Leaflet, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 71)
  - Natural Gas Group, 1995 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 72)
  - Natural World, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 73)
  - Newsletters, 1970-1972; 1975; 1985; 1995-1996; 1999-2001 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 74)
  - New York League of Conservation Voters, Correspondence, 1992 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 75)
  - New York Environmental News, Memorandum, 1973 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 76)
  - New York Public Interest Research Group, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 77)
  - New York State Association of Conservation Commissioners, 1972-1975 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 78)
  - New York State Association for Reduction, Reuse, and Recycling, Leaflet, Undated (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 79)
  - New York State Association of Environmental Management Councils, Newsletter, 1993 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 80)
  - New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, Department of Natural Resources, Questionnaire, 1991 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 81)
  - New York State Conference on the Environment, Flier, 1994 (Box 2 (8-Subject Files), Folder 82)
  - New York State Department of Environmental Conservation, 1983; 1992-1994; Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - New York State Department of Environmental Conservation, Information Leaflets, 1963; 1966-1970; 1973 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - New York State Department of Environmental Conservation, News Releases, 1991-1994 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - New York State Department of Environmental Conservation, Pamphlets, 1983; 1988; 1991 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - New York State Department of Health, 1990-1991; 1993-1995 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - New York State Energy Research and Development Authority, 1992; Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - New York State Environmental Facilities Corporation, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - New York State Legislative Commission on Toxic Substances and Hazardous Wastes, 1994 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - New York State Urban Environment Conference, 1973 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Noise Pollution, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Northeast Sustainable Energy Association, Fliers, 1994; Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Oceans, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Oil Pollution, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Organizations, Miscellaneous, 1975; Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Orion Society, 1995-1996 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Outlines of Work to Be Done, Notes, 1975 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Patton's Products, 1995 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Peoples Bicentennial Committee, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - "The Perceptual Environment: Quality Assessment in the Capital District," Capital District Regional Planning Commission, 1975 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Periodicals for Conservation Commissions, Department of Environmental Conservation, 1971-1972 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Pesticides, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Philosophy and Ethics, News Clippings, 1969-1976 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Phosphates, 1970-1971 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Pine Bush Alternative Master Plan, Discussion Draft, 1975 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - "Pitch In" Anti-litter Campaign, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Planet Drum Foundation, 1992; 1994; Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Poisons, News Clippings, 1969 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Pollution, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Politics, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - "Pollution Prevention Guidance for Small Business and Local Government," Department of Environmental Conservation, 1995 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - "Popeye and Environmental Careers," Comic Book, 1973 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Population, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Population Growth, 1971; Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Portraits, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Power and Energy Industries, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - "A Preliminary Housing Plan for the Capital District Region," Capital District Regional Planning Commission, 1972 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Preservation League of New York, 1977-1979 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Preservation of Historic Buildings, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Preservation of Wilderness, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Problems and Goals, Research Sources, Jackson Davis, 1976-1977 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Radioactive Wastes, News Clippings, 1969-1970; 1989-1990 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Reclamation of Land, News Clippings, 1969 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Recreation, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Recreation Support Program for Disadvantaged Youth, Program Proposal, 1972 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Recycled Paper, Albany County Use of, 1970/1971 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Recycling, Reports, Articles, 1971-1973 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Regional Cooperation, 1972 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Regional Environmental Management, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Rensselaer County Environmental Management Council, 1995 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Rensselaer County Soil and Water Conservation District, Newsletters, 1991 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Rensselaer Planning Perspectives, Newsletters, 1973 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Rensselaer Taconic Land Conservancy, 1995 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - "Report of the Steering Committee on New Federalism", 1975 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - "Report on Preliminary Meeting of Agencies Interested in Cooperative Planning and Fund Raising for Latin-American Development...", Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - River Voices, Newsletters, 1992-1994 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Roman Catholic Diocese of Albany, 1995 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Saratoga County Land Conservancy, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Save the Pine Bush, Leaflet, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Schenectady City Recycling Program, Leaflet, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Schenectady Community Action Program Rappin' with SCAP, Newsletter, 1974 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - Schenectady County Environmental Advisory Council, Leaflets, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 61)
  - Schenectady County Save Our Resources Today (S.O.R.T.), 1994; Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 62)
  - Science Education, 1972-1973 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 63)
  - Semantics, News Clippings, 1969 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 64)
  - "So Many for So Few: An Inventory of the Governments in the Capital District of New York State", 1971 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 65)
  - "Social Benefit Corporations?" Robert Louis Schultz, 1971 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 66)
  - Social Justice Center, 1997; Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 67)
  - Solar Energy Articles, 1972-1975 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 68)
  - Solid Waste and Recycling, 1970; 1972-1973; Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 69)
  - Speakers, Contact Information, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 70)
  - "The State of the Region," Capital District Regional Planning Commission, 1975 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 71)
  - Storm Water Permit Workshops, 1994 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 72)
  - Student Council on Pollution and the Environment, 1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 73)
  - SUNY College of Environmental Science and Forestry, 1991; 1993-1994; Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 74)
  - Technology and Industry, News Clippings, 1969 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 75)
  - Thermal Pollution, News Clippings, 1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 76)
  - "Toxic Air Pollution: The Unseen Enemy," American Lung Association, Pamphlet, 1985 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 77)
  - "Towards a National Coordinating Committee for Action to Solve the Problems of Our Environment," Jackson Davis, Notes, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 78)
  - "A Training Program for Citizen Conservationists in Community Resources Inventory," James Edward Ashton, 1972 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 79)
  - Transportation, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 80)
  - Urban Problems, News Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 81)
  - U.S.D.A. Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service, 1965; 1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 82)
  - U.S. Government Agencies Involved in Environmental Problems, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 83)
  - Visual Pollution, News Clippings, 1969/1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 84)
  - Waste Disposal, News Clippings, 1969/1970 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 85)
  - Water and Waste Pollution, News Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 86)
  - Water Courses, Newsletter, 1994; 1996-1997 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 87)
  - Water Environment Federation, Leaflet, 1993 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 88)
  - Wetlands, Marshes and Tidal Areas, News Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 89)
  - Whiteman, Osterman and Hanna, News Clippings, 1995 (Box 4 (8-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Wild Earth, 1992 (Box 4 (8-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Wildlife Preservation, News Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 4 (8-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Wood Burning, Biomass Energy Production, 1977-1978 (Box 4 (8-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Wood Burning, Home Heating, 1977-1978; 1982 (Box 4 (8-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - "Year Book of World Problems and Human Potential," Union of International Associations, 1976 (Box 4 (8-Subject Files), Folder 6)
- News Clippings, 1968-1996; Undated; 9; 0.5 cubic ft.
  Arranged chronologically.
  The majority of this series is a collection of unsorted news clippings and articles collected by Jackson Davis, with a single folder of clippings collected by Lou Ismay. The bulk of the articles date from between 1968 and 1973 and deal with environmental issues of the day, such as the use of the pesticide DDT, environmental concerns about the proposed supersonic transport (SST) plane, and the ecology of the Adirondacks.
  - News Clippings, 1968-1969 (Box 1 (9-News Clippings), Folder 1)
  - News Clippings, 1970 (Box 1 (9-News Clippings), Folder 2)
  - News Clippings, 1970 (Box 1 (9-News Clippings), Folder 3)
  - News Clippings, Collected by Lou Ismay, 1970 (Box 1 (9-News Clippings), Folder 4)
  - News Clippings, Daily Pollution Index, 1970 (Box 1 (9-News Clippings), Folder 5)
  - News Clippings, 1971 (Box 1 (9-News Clippings), Folder 6)
  - News Clippings, 1971 (Box 1 (9-News Clippings), Folder 7)
  - News Clippings, "The New York Times Magazine", 1971 (Box 1 (9-News Clippings), Folder 8)
  - News Clippings, 1972 (Box 2 (9-News Clippings), Folder 1)
  - News Clippings, 1973 (Box 2 (9-News Clippings), Folder 2)
  - News Clippings, 1973 (Box 2 (9-News Clippings), Folder 3)
  - News Clippings, 1975 (Box 2 (9-News Clippings), Folder 4)
  - News Clippings, 1978; 1985; 1994-1996 (Box 2 (9-News Clippings), Folder 5)
  - News Clippings, Undated (Box 2 (9-News Clippings), Folder 6)